<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<!--Contents of Recipes table in RecipeOrganizer database-->
<Recipes>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>1</RecipeID>
    <Title>Mexican Pozole</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>1 cup
Each serving provides:
Calories:  253
Total fat:  10 g
Saturated fat:  3 g
Cholesterol:  52 mg
Sodium:  425 mg
Calcium:  28 mg
Iron:  3 mg</ServingSize>
    <Yield>10 servings    </Yield>
    <Directions>1.  In a large pot, heat oil.  Saute beef. 
2.  Add onion, garlic, salt, pepper, cilantro, and enough
water to cover the meat.  Cover pot and cook over low heat
until meat is tender.
3.  Add tomatoes and tomato paste.  Continue cooking for
about 20 minutes.
4.  Add hominy and continue cooking another 15 minutes,
stirring occasionally, over low heat.  If too thick, add
water for desired consistency.</Directions>
    <Comment>Only a small amount of oil is needed to saute meat. Option: Skinless, 
boneless chicken breasts may be used instead of beef cubes.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>2</RecipeID>
    <Title>Stir-Fried Beef</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>1 1/4 cup
Each serving with potatoes 
and rice provides:
Calories:  549
Total fat:  8 g
Saturated fat:  2 g
Cholesterol:  56 mg
Sodium:  288 mg
Calcium:  55 mg
Iron:  5 mg</ServingSize>
    <Yield>6 servings     </Yield>
    <Directions>1.  In a large skillet, heat oil and saute garlic until
garlic is golden.  Add steak, vinegar, salt, and pepper.
2.  Cook for 6 minutes, stirring beef until brown.
3.  Add onion and tomato.  Cook until onion is transparent. 
4.	Serve with boiled potatoes and white rice.</Directions>
    <Comment>Trim fat from steak and cut into small, thin pieces.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>3</RecipeID>
    <Title>Chicken Stew</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>1 piece of chicken
Each serving provides:
Calories:  206
Total fat:  6 g
Saturated fat:  2 g
Cholesterol:  75 mg
Sodium:  489 mg
Calcium:  32 mg
Iron:  2 mg</ServingSize>
    <Yield>8 servings     </Yield>
    <Directions>1.	In a large skillet, combine chicken, water, garlic, onion,
salt, pepper, tomatoes, and parsley.  Tightly cover and cook
over low heat for 25 minutes.
2.  Add celery, potatoes, carrots, and bay leaves and
continue to cook for 15 more minutes or until chicken and 
vegetables are tender.  Remove bay leaves before serving.</Directions>
    <Comment>Remove the skin from the chicken and any extra fat.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>4</RecipeID>
    <Title>Grilled Chicken With Green Chile Sauce</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>1 breast
Each serving provides:
Calories:  192
Total fat:  5 g
Saturated fat:  2 g
Cholesterol:  71 mg
Sodium:  220 mg
Calcium:  53 mg
Iron:  2 mg</ServingSize>
    <Yield>4 servings     </Yield>
    <Directions>1.	Combine the oil, juice from one lime, oregano, and black
pepper in a shallow glass baking dish.  Stir.  Place the
chicken breasts in the baking dish and turn to coat each
side.  Cover the dish and refrigerate overnight.  Turn the
chicken periodically to marinate chicken on both sides.
2.  Put water, tomatillos, and onion into a saucepan.  Bring
to a gentle boil and cook uncovered for 10 minutes or until
the tomatillos are tender.  In a blender, place the cooked
onion, tomatillos, and any remaining water.  Add the garlic,
peppers, cilantro, salt, and the remaining lime juice. 
Blend until all the ingredients are smooth.  Place the sauce
in a bowl and refrigerate.
3.  Place the chicken breasts on a hot grill and cook until
done.  Place the chicken on a serving platter.
4.  Spoon a tablespoon of low fat sour cream over each
chicken breast.  Pour the sauce over the sour cream.</Directions>
    <Comment>Marinate meats to make them tender without adding a lot of
fat.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>5</RecipeID>
    <Title>Caribbean Pink Beans</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>1/2 cup
Each serving provides:
Calories:  133
Total fat:  Less than 1 g
Saturated fat:  Less than 1 g
Cholesterol:  0 mg
Sodium:  205 mg
Calcium:  39 mg
Iron:  2 mg</ServingSize>
    <Yield>16 servings    </Yield>
    <Directions>1.  Rinse and pick through the beans.  Put the beans in a
large pot and add 10 cups of water.  Place the pot in the
refrigerator and allow the beans to soak overnight.
2.  Cook the beans until they are soft.  Add more water as
needed while the beans are cooking.
3.  Add the plantains, tomato, pepper, onion, garlic, and
salt.  Continue cooking at low heat until the plantains are
soft.
4.	Serve with rice (optional).</Directions>
    <Comment>Use no lard or other fat to make beans.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>6</RecipeID>
    <Title>Chayotes Stuffed With Cheese</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>2 chayote halves
Each serving provides:
Calories:  129
Total fat:  6 g
Saturated fat:  2 g
Cholesterol:  11 mg
Sodium:  276 mg
Calcium:  163 mg
Iron:  1 mg</ServingSize>
    <Yield>6 servings     </Yield>
    <Directions>1.  Wash chayotes and bring to a boil in water.  Cover and
boil at moderate heat for about 1 hour or until fork-tender.
2.  Preheat oven to 350 degrees.
3.  Drain chayotes, remove cores and fibrous part under
cores.  Scoop out pulp, being careful not to break shells. 
Place shells on cookie sheet.
4.  Immediately mash pulp and mix with cheese, salt, and
margarine.
5.  Stuff shells with the mixture.  Sprinkle with bread
crumbs.
6.  Bake for 30 minutes.</Directions>
    <Comment>This heart-healthy dish uses low fat cheese and a small
amount of margarine.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>7</RecipeID>
    <Title>Home-made Sour Cream</Title>
    <RecipeType>Dessert     </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>2 1/2 tablespoons
Each serving provides:
Calories:  27
Total fat:  Less than 1 g
Saturated fat:  Less than 1 g
Cholesterol:  2 mg
Sodium:  117 mg
Calcium:  24 mg
Iron:  Less than 1 mg</ServingSize>
    <Yield>8 servings     </Yield>
    <Directions>1.  Place all ingredients in a blender, and combine on
medium-high speed until smooth and creamy.
2.	Serve with Tropical Fruit Compote or any 
recipe that uses sour cream.</Directions>
    <Comment>Try this instead of sour cream on beans, vegetables, fruit,
and tortillas.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>8</RecipeID>
    <Title>Rice Pudding</Title>
    <RecipeType>Dessert     </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>1/2 cup
Each serving provides:
Calories:  372
Total fat:  Less than 1 g
Saturated fat:  Less than 1 g
Cholesterol:  3 mg
Sodium:  366 mg
Calcium:  255 mg
Iron:  2 mg</ServingSize>
    <Yield>5 servings     </Yield>
    <Directions>1.  Put the water and cinnamon sticks into a medium
saucepan.  Bring to a boil.
2.  Stir in rice.  Cook on low heat for 30 minutes until
rice is soft and water has evaporated.
3.  Add skim milk, sugar, and salt.  Cook for another 15
minutes until it thickens.</Directions>
    <Comment>Use skim milk instead of whole milk to reduce fat and
calories.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>9</RecipeID>
    <Title>Tropical Fruit Compote</Title>
    <RecipeType>Dessert     </RecipeType>
    <Directions>1.  In a saucepan combine 3/4 cup of water with the sugar,
lemon juice, and lemon peel (and rum or vanilla extract if
desired).  Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat and add the
fruit.  Cook at a very low heat for 5 minutes.
2.  Pour the syrup in a cup.  Remove the lemon rind and cool
the cooked fruit for 2 hours.
3.  To serve the compote, arrange the fruit in a serving
dish and pour a few teaspoons of syrup over the fruit. 
Garnish with mint leaves.
4.	Serve with Home-made Sour Cream</Directions>
    <Comment>Fresh or cooked fruits make a great low-calorie dessert.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>11</RecipeID>
    <Title>Shake-It-Up Chicken Nuggets</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>4 nuggets</ServingSize>
    <Yield>4 servings     </Yield>
    <Directions>1. Preheat oven to 450 degrees F.
2. Measure stuffing mix into resealable plastic bag. Seal bag and
place on flat surface. Crush crumbs by rolling and pressing rolling
pin over bag.
3. Open bag and add Parmesan cheese. Reseal bag and shake to mix
thoroughly.
4. Melt margarine (see Cook's Note)
5. Place melted margarine, buttermilk, and pepper in medium shallow
bowl. Stir well with spoon. Set aside.
6. Rinse chicken breasts and pat dry with paper towels.
7. Place chicken breasts on cutting board. Cut chicken with small,
sharp knife into 16 chunks of the same size. (Each chicken breast
should give you 8 chunks or pieces.)
8. Dip each chicken chunk into buttermilk mixture, covering all sides.
Let extra buttermilk mixture drip off. Place 3 dipped chunks at a time
into bag of crumbs. Seal bag tightly and shake until chicken pieces
are evenly coated with crumbs.
9. Place coated nuggets on an ungreased baking sheet. Repeat with
remaining chicken chunks.
10. Place baking sheet in oven. Bake nuggets 4 minutes.
11. With oven mitts, remove pan from oven. Using tongs, turn over each
nugget.
12. Return to oven and bake 4 to 5 minutes, or until medium golden
brown.
13. With oven mitts, remove pan from oven. Using tongs, remove nuggets
to platter or plates. Serve nuggets immediately. Place a small bowl of
your favorite dipping sauce nearby, if you like.

Cook's Note

You can use the stovetop or the microwave to melt margarine. If you
choose a stick margarine, it can easily be measured by looking at the
tablespoon markings on the wrapper and cutting off the amount you
need. Each stick equals 8 tablespoons. To melt the margarine, follow
these easy steps:

Stovetop
Place margarine in small saucepan.
Place saucepan on burner.
Turn heat to low.
Heat until margarine melts, stirring occasionally.

Microwave
Place margarine in small microwave-safe bowl.
Cover with waxed paper.
Microwave on HIGH (100 % power) 30 to 45 seconds for 1 tablespoon, or
45 to 60 seconds for 1/4 cup.</Directions>
    <Comment>Chicken nuggets are usually deep-fried in hot oil to give them a
crusty coating. But all that oil makes the nuggets greasy. In our
recipe, the chicken is tossed in a bag with seasoned stuffing mix and
grated Parmesan cheese. It is then baked in the oven. These
"oven-fried" nuggets are crisp and golden. But, they don't have that
extra fat you get from deep-frying.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>12</RecipeID>
    <Title>Slumber Party French Toast</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>1 slice</ServingSize>
    <Yield>6 servings     </Yield>
    <Directions>1. Place margarine in baking pan or heat-proof 13-by-9 baking dish. Place pan
on burner. Turn heat to low. Heat margarine until melted.
2. Place brown sugar in small bowl. With fork, stir in cinnamon.
Sprinkle mixture evenly over melted margarine in baking pan or dish.
3. Combine egg substitute and milk in glass pie plate. Mix with fork
until blended.
4. With fingers or fork, dip bread slices into egg mixture to coat
both sides. Lay slices over sugar-cinnamon mixture in baking pan or
dish. Pour any remaining egg mixture over the bread slices.
5. Cover pan with foil and refrigerate overnight.
6. Remove pan from refrigerator 1 hour before baking. Let stand on the
kitchen counter to reach room temperature.
7. Preheat oven to 375 degrees F.
8. Carefully place pan of French toast in hot oven. Bake 25 minutes.
9. Using oven mitts, remove pan from oven to wire cooling rack. With
oven mitts, carefully remove foil from pan.
10. Return pan to hot oven. Bake for 15 minutes longer.
11. Using oven mitts, remove pan to cooling rack. Sprinkle French
toast with powdered sugar. Serve warm.
Cook's Notes
1. Here's a terrific breakfast treat, but to make it you'll need to
think ahead. You need to start this recipe the day before you serve
it, since it must be refrigerated overnight. Use crusty loaves of
French bread cut into slices. Regular white bread slices won't work --
they're too soft and will get soggy.
2. When measuring brown sugar, follow these simple steps: Spoon the
brown sugar out of its box into the correct size dry measuring cup.
With your hand on the back of a wooden spoon, push the brown sugar
into the measuring cup to "pack" it.
Continue spooning in the sugar and packing it down until the cup is
full and level on the top.
When directed in the recipe to add the brown sugar, turn the cup
upside down into the bowl. The sugar should come out easily and hold
its "cup" shape.</Directions>
    <Comment>This French toast is a bit different from the usual kind. The bread is
first dipped into a sweetened cinnamon-flavored batter, then set in
refrigerator overnight to absorb the delicious flavors. The next
morning, it's baked rather than fried. What a way to start the day
with sleepover friends or your own family.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>13</RecipeID>
    <Title>Top Hat Pizza</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Yield>1 serving      </Yield>
    <Directions>1. Peel and chop onion (see Cook's Note). Measure out 2 teaspoons and
set aside. (Save the rest to use in another recipe.)
2. Rinse bell pepper and place on cutting board. Remove seeds and
white pith from inside the pepper. With small, sharp knife, chop bell
pepper. Measure out 1 tablespoon and set aside. (Save the rest to use
in another recipe.)
3. Grate cheese if it is not pre-shredded (see Cook's Note)
4. Preheat oven to 400 degrees F.
5. Using kitchen scissors cut out a circle from top layer of the pita
bread, leaving 1 inch of top all around to form an edge or border.
Same cut-out circle.
6. Place bottom of pita on cookie sheet or baking sheet. Using oven
mitts, put on middle rack in hot oven. Bake 5 minutes.
7. With oven mitts, carefully remove from oven and place pan on wire
cooling rack. Cool slightly.
8. Place cooled pita on cutting board. Using small spatula or spoon,
spread pizza sauce evenly on top and also under the edge of the pita
bread. Sprinkle bell pepper, onion, Italian seasoning, and mozzarella
cheese evenly on top of sauce. Top with reserved circle of pita bead
to form a "hat."
9. Return completed pizza to cookie sheet or baking sheet. Bake in hot
oven for 8 to 9 minutes.
10. With oven mitts, carefully remove pan from oven to cooling rack.
11. Sprinkle with Parmesan cheese and let stand a few minutes.
12. Place pizza on cutting board. Cut in half with kitchen scissors,
small knife, or pizza cutter. Serve hot.
Cook's Note
To grate your own cheese, follow these directions:
Place the grater in a bowl.
Hold the grater firmly in one hand and place a large piece of cheese
in other hand.
Rub the cheese against the small holes of the grater. (The cheese will
come out in shreds.)
Be careful not to rub your knuckles against the grater.</Directions>
    <Comment>If you always thought pizza wasn't a nutritious food, think again.
This one has a delicious combination of vitamin-packed peppers,
low-fat cheese, and whole-wheat bread. It's great for a quick snack,
lunch, or supper.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>14</RecipeID>
    <Title>Cream Sauce</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Directions>In blender put lime juice, cilantro and 2/3 of the jalapeno's. Blend
until smooth. Add sour cream, blend and taste. Add salt and taste. Add
remaining jalapeno's if necessary.</Directions>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>15</RecipeID>
    <Title>Papaya Pineapple Relish</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Directions>Mix together and let sit for 1/2 hour.</Directions>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>16</RecipeID>
    <Title>Halibut - with papaya pineapple relish</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Directions>Season the halibut and pan sear until done. Place rice in center of
plate. Place fish in top of rice and top with the relish and then the
fried carrot. Place sprig and lemon wedge on plate. Make sure to
drizzle some of the relish liquid around the plate.</Directions>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>17</RecipeID>
    <Title>Crab Cakes</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Directions>In a large bowl put peppers and seasonings to taste. Add cream and
crab being careful not to break up the crab too much. Add panko and
coriander. Add beaten eggs and form patty to test for consistency. It
should be somewhat light, not a dense glass breaking cake. If okay,
then form into 1 3/4 oz balls and shape into patties. Toss in panko
and place in a hotel pan divided by wax paper. saute and serve with
Jalapeno Cilantro cream</Directions>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>18</RecipeID>
    <Title>Seafood Pineapple Ceviche</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Directions>Mix the first 4 ingredients together and set aside.
Fry the tortilla bowl by pushing down into fryer with the backside of
a 6 oz ladle.
Cut other tortillas into wedges and fry till golden and crispy
Cut the fish into small cubes and marinate with the shrimp and
scallops in a mix of half lemon and half lime juices.  Cover and
refrigerate overnight.
Toss cooked ceviche with a 2 oz ladel full of the fruit mix.  Place a
small scoop of rice in the center of the plate and place a tortilla
bowl on the rice.  Place the ceviche in the tortilla bowl and garnish
with scallop on the half shell, fried tortilla chips and fried
parsley.</Directions>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>19</RecipeID>
    <Title>Shrimp Scampi</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Directions>Start with a hot pan. Add tbsp of olive oil. Add shrimp and saute for
2 minutes. Add garlic and saute until toasted. Add tomatoes and
deglaze with sherry. Season with salt and pepper. Finish with butter
and add fresh basil.</Directions>
    <Comment>This dish can be prepared with a variety of items beside shrimp.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>20</RecipeID>
    <Title>Rustic sundried tomato and walnut pesto</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Directions>Start with a hot pan. Add tbsp of olive oil. Add garlic and saute for
2 minutes, let cool. Mix all ingredients together.</Directions>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>21</RecipeID>
    <Title>Steamed Clams</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <Directions>Start with a hot pan. Add tbsp of olive oil. Add clams and saute for 2
minutes. Add garlic and saute until toasted. Deglaze with white wine,
season with chili flakes, and pepper. Do not salt as clams are
naturally salty. Cover and simmer for 6-7 minutes or until clams have
opened. Finish with butter and chopped parsley.

Serve with lemons and bread.</Directions>
    <Comment>Clams contain sand and sediment. To remove most of this, soak
clams in cold fresh water for 10-15 minutes. Clams will expel most of
what sand they contain.</Comment>
  </Recipe>
  <Recipe>
    <RecipeID>22</RecipeID>
    <Title>Oyster Rockefeller Soup</Title>
    <RecipeType>Meal Item   </RecipeType>
    <ServingSize>8 oz.</ServingSize>
    <Yield>10 servings    </Yield>
    <Directions>Saute onion in a little butter until translucent. Add spinach and
season with salt &amp; generous amount of pepper. Sweat for three minutes
until spinach is wilted and then deglaze with Ouzo. Reduce until
almost dry and then add heavy cream and clam juice. Simmer for ten
minutes and then blend. Coat oysters with panko and fry until crispy.
Saute prosciutto (how much depends on how much you like it) until
crispy and add to soup along with fried oysters.</Directions>
  </Recipe>
</Recipes>